Ann-Cathrin Will - Front-end developer

Woking, Surrey ann@cathrinwill.com | www.cathrinwill.com

Profile

I'm an experienced front-end developer having worked at a variety of digital and marketing agencies for over 3 years. With strong skills in writing HMTL and CSS, utilising Sass and Grunt for development.

As a front-end developer I'm always trying to improve on workflow by utilising task runners, making code more modular, maintainable and semantic as web standards progress and keeping load times to a minimum.

Skills Summary

Core Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- Sass/SCSS
- LESS
- ¡Query
- JavaScript
- Grunt

- Responsive Design
- Progressive enhancement
- W3C Standards & Accessibility
- Usability & UX considerations
- Cross browser compatibility
- Version control (Git)
- Adobe Suite (Illustrator & Photoshop)

Professional Experience

Front end Developer at Purple Agency

March 2013 – Present

- Building front-end responsive templates based on supplied designs using SCSS/LESS and grunt/gulp.
- Cross browser and A/B testing.
- Building and setting up responsive email campaigns.
- Keeping clean and maintainable code.
- Staying up to date with web trends and new technologies.
- Ensuring websites are accessibility friendly.
- Using semantic code, meta/micro data, and google analytics, to ensure SEO for sites.
- Using a combination of git, bitbucket, SourceTree and SVN for version control.

Front end Developer at Webexpectations

September 2012 – March 2013

- Building the front end from Photoshop/Illustrator templates, and creating standalone pages for multivariate testing.
- Experience gained from working with a variety of CMS'.

Ann-Cathrin Will - Front-end developer

Woking, Surrey ann@cathrinwill.com | www.cathrinwill.com

- Working with development processes including git for version control.
- Experience with responsive web development and mobile / retina display optimisation.
- Built HTML Emails and HTML email signatures.

Junior Web Developer at SuperReal GmbH, Germany April 2007 – October 2007

Work experience in Hamburg learning how to make websites, working with graphic designers and using Photoshop and Integrating front-end code with code written by backend developers. Taking extra care to make websites identical across browsers including such challenges as IE6/7 and the box model bug.

Education

Web Development with Business BSc (Hons), Kingston University 2009 – 2012

- Learned the foundations to several previously self taught languages.
- Got a basic understanding of a variety of web languages.
- Worked in a lot of groups often taking on the role of organiser within it.
- Always ensured to hand in every coursework before the deadline.
- Helped peers with their work, and vice versa learned a lot from them.
- Thoroughly enjoyed working on the Single Semester Final Year Project, the end result which can be viewed on http://pixxy.cathrinwill.com/

Computer Information Systems and Mathematics Foundation 2008 – 2009 Kingston College, Kingston upon Thames

Interests

Apart from keeping up to date with anything surrounding web development by subscribing to a number of blogs, I greatly enjoy sunshine, hiking, science and reading.

Languages

English (Bilingual proficiency)
German (Bilingual proficiency)

References

Available on request.